Richard George Heck

whattherichard.github.io linkedin.com/in/hecktech

Indianapolis, IN (317) 460-6310 whatthegeorge@gmail.com

I desire to be part of a team that is enthusiastically engaged in discovering technologies that enrich lives and solve problems. I have an analytical, problem solving mind and am passionate about developing the future of technology and the community it can create. My background has been in leadership and people skills with a recent swing into developing with Node.js and different development management techniques including Agile methodologies. Previous jobs and training have taught me how to encourage and motivate members to work effectively as a group.

WORK EXPERIENCE -

Self-Employed (August 2017 - Present)

 JavaScript Developer - specializing in web sites and Full-Stack web-based applications using Node.js, GitHub, HTML, CSS, SQL, React, and Angular

Brad Osborne Real Estate P.C. (2017 - 2018)

- Personal Assistant organized and maintained office filing system; assisted with finances and project management; daily check in and updates; streamlined processes and created system of prioritization for daily tasks ensuring efficiency Ransburg Scout Reservation (Summer 2014, 2016)
 - High Adventure Instructor and Certified COPE Director lived on campgrounds through summer instructing and leading Scouts through the Climbing Merit Badge and COPE (challenge obstacle course)
 - Volunteered weekly and taught "Climb On Safely" course to adult troop leaders

Ed Martin Acura (2015 - 2016)

• Detailer/Lot Assistant/Porter - Self-managed tasks; cleaned and detailed cars; valet of vehicles; seasonal showroom arrangement; maintaining front and back stock lots; pick up and drop-off customers

REGO-Fix (2013 - 2014)

• Warehouse Technician - Re-categorized warehouse inventory with new database system increasing productivity and efficiency 50%, allowing for promotions

Byron Fellowship (2011 - 2013)

• Director of Communications - Coordinated nominee application and screening process, assisted in preparing attendees and instructors for course work, management of online profiles and accommodations; assisted and participated in implementation of course sessions; established social media presence on Facebook, LinkedIn, and Twitter; established Salesforce application setup and email protocols; maintained website

NOTE: Gaps in employment were filled with various restaurant positions focused in customer service and sales

CERTIFICATES -

Minister - American Marriage Ministries (2017)

COPE Director - National Camp School (2014)

- Became proficient leading groups safely through teambuilding obstacles, facilitating personal and team development
- Mastered the ability to safely instruct and operate an outdoor artificial climbing facility

Byron Fellow - Byron Fellowship (2011)

- Focus on Sustainability and Leadership; place-based learning, with the evolution of group structures and communities 1st Dan Black Belt North Indy Taekwondo (2008 2014)
 - Learned patience, discipline and self-control; assisted in instructing lower belt levels

COMMUNITY ACTIVITIES -

City of Carmel (2006 - present)

- Initiated new social media protocol using social media analytics and SnapChat geocaching
- Assisted with the setup, implementation and takedown of large-scale community events including Holiday on the Square, Carmelfest, International Arts Festival and Jazz on the Monon
- Assisted in production of various government cable channel programs
- Video talent for Artomobilia, Jazz on the Monon and Carmel Teen Police Academy

EDUCATION -

Eleven Fifty Academy, JavaScript 151-8 week, 201-1 week, 301-1 week (2017)

• Built multiple Full-Stack web applications using Node.js, GitHub, Heroku, Angular, React/Redux, HTML/CSS (with heavy testing and de-bugging); built a portfolio; became skilled in Agile fundamentals and public speaking

Ivy Tech, General Studies (2011 - 2014)

• General Studies, focused on Economics and Physics

Carmel High School, Core 40 (2011)

Pre-law college courses